<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="GSheetImporter" inherits="RefCounted" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../../doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		A utility class for importing and parsing data from Google Sheets.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		GSheetImporter provides functionality to fetch and parse data from Google Sheets documents. It handles HTTP requests to the Google Sheets API, parses the JSON response, and emits the data in a structured format.

		The importer supports progress tracking through progress bar methods and automatically handles resource saving with conflict detection.

		There are two ways to use this class through GDScript files placed in the [code]res://importers/[/code] folder:

		[b]1. As a Google Sheet Importer:[/b]
		Create a script that implements the following methods:
		[codeblock]
		class_name MySheetImporter
		extends GSheetImporter

		func get_sheet_id() -> String:
		    return "1234567890abcdef" # Your Google Sheet ID

		func get_sheet_name() -> String:
		    return "Sheet1" # Your sheet name

		func on_imported_data(import_type: String, data: Array) -> void:
		    for entry in data:
		        print("Imported row: ", entry)
		[/codeblock]

		[b]2. As a Custom Menu Item:[/b]
		Create a script that implements these methods instead:
		[codeblock]
		class_name MyCustomMenuItem
		extends GSheetImporter

		func get_menu_name() -> String:
		    return "My Custom Action" # This will appear in the editor's tool menu

		func on_menu_clicked() -> void:
		    # Your custom logic here
		    print("Custom menu item clicked!")
		[/codeblock]

		[b]Editor Integration:[/b]
		When running in the editor, the class automatically:
		- Scans the [code]res://importers/[/code] directory for .gd files
		- For sheet importers: Adds an "Import {sheet_name}" entry to the editor's tool menu
		- For custom menu items: Adds the [method get_menu_name] result to the tool menu
		- Handles progress bars automatically through the editor's progress display
		- Manages cleanup and reloading of menu items

		[b]Note:[/b] The [code]res://importers/[/code] directory must exist for the automatic script detection to work.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="end_import_progress_bar">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Signals the end of an import operation's progress tracking. This method is called automatically when the import process completes, but can also be called manually if needed.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_sheet_id" qualifiers="virtual const">
			<return type="String" />
			<description>
				Virtual method that must be implemented by inheriting classes to provide the Google Sheet ID.
				The Sheet ID can be found in the Google Sheets URL between /d/ and /edit.

				Example URL: https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/[b]1234567890abcdef[/b]/edit
				The sheet ID would be "1234567890abcdef"
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_sheet_name" qualifiers="virtual const">
			<return type="String" />
			<description>
				Virtual method that must be implemented by inheriting classes to provide the sheet name to import.
				This is the name of the specific sheet tab in the Google Sheets document.

				Note: If the sheet name contains spaces, they will be automatically encoded in the URL.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="on_imported_data" qualifiers="virtual">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="import_type" type="String" />
			<param index="1" name="data" type="Array" />
			<description>
				Virtual method called when data has been successfully imported and parsed.
				[param import_type] is the sheet name that was imported.
				[param data] is an Array of Dictionary objects, where each Dictionary represents a row from the sheet with column headers as keys.

				Example implementation:
				[codeblock]
				func on_imported_data(import_type: String, data: Array) -> void:
				    for row in data:
				        var name = row["Name"]
				        var value = row["Value"]
				        print("Imported: ", name, " = ", value)
				[/codeblock]
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="request_import">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Initiates the import process by sending an HTTP request to the Google Sheets API.
				The method automatically handles the creation of the HTTP request and connection setup.
				
				The imported data will be delivered through the [signal imported_data] signal and the [method on_imported_data] virtual method.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="save_resource_if_different">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="resource_path" type="String" />
			<param index="1" name="resource" type="Resource" />
			<description>
				Saves a resource to disk only if it differs from an existing resource at the same path.
				This method includes smart diffing to only update changed properties.

				[param resource_path] is the path where the resource should be saved.
				[param resource] is the Resource instance to save.

				If a resource already exists at the specified path, it will:
				1. Compare the new resource with the existing one
				2. Update only the changed properties in the existing resource
				3. Save only if changes were detected
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="start_import_progress_bar">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="steps" type="int" />
			<param index="1" name="task_name" type="String" />
			<param index="2" name="task_description" type="String" />
			<description>
				Initializes a progress bar for tracking the import process.
				
				[param steps] is the total number of steps in the operation.
				[param task_name] is a short name for the import task.
				[param task_description] is a longer description of what's being imported.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="step_import_progress_bar">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="step" type="int" />
			<param index="1" name="step_description" type="String" />
			<description>
				Updates the import progress bar to the specified step.
				
				[param step] is the current step number (should be between 0 and the total steps specified in [method start_import_progress_bar]).
				[param step_description] is a description of the current step being executed.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
	<signals>
		<signal name="imported_data">
			<param index="0" name="import_type" type="String" />
			<param index="1" name="data" type="Array" />
			<description>
				Emitted when data has been successfully imported and parsed from the Google Sheet.
				[param import_type] contains the sheet name that was imported.
				[param data] contains an Array of Dictionary objects representing the imported rows.
				
				Each dictionary in the data array uses the sheet's column headers as keys and the cell values as values.
			</description>
		</signal>
	</signals>
</class>
