<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="YSaveable3D" inherits="Node" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../../doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		A node that enables automatic saving and loading of 3D scene nodes with their transforms and metadata.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		YSaveable3D is a helper node that works in conjunction with [YSave] to automatically save and load 3D scene nodes. When added as a child to a Node3D, it will:
		- Save the node's position, rotation, and scale
		- Save all metadata attached to the node
		- Handle automatic loading and spawning of saved nodes
		- Manage cleanup of saved nodes during scene transitions

		Example of basic usage:
		[codeblock]
		# In your scene setup:
		var saveable_node = YSaveable3D.new()
		your_3d_node.add_child(saveable_node)
		
		# Add metadata to be saved
		your_3d_node.set_meta("health", 100)
		your_3d_node.set_meta("inventory", ["sword", "shield"])
		
		# The node's transform and metadata will be automatically saved
		# when YSave.request_save() is called
		[/codeblock]

		The node will automatically save:
		- Global position ("p")
		- Global rotation ("r") if different from original
		- Scale ("s") if different from original
		- Node name ("n") if not an internal name
		- Scene path ID ("scn") for proper instantiation
		- All metadata that doesn't start with "_"
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="_on_load_save" qualifiers="virtual">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="saved_values" type="Dictionary" />
			<description>
				Virtual method called when saved values are loaded. Override this method to handle custom loading logic.

				[param saved_values] contains all the saved data for this node, including transforms and metadata.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="_on_prepare_save" qualifiers="virtual const">
			<return type="bool" />
			<param index="0" name="save_values" type="Dictionary" />
			<description>
				Virtual method called before saving. Override this method to add custom save logic or prevent saving.

				Return [code]false[/code] to prevent the node from being saved, [code]true[/code] to proceed with saving.
				[param save_values] contains the current values to be saved, which can be modified before saving.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="cleanup_all_saved_nodes" qualifiers="static">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Static method that triggers cleanup of all YSaveable3D nodes in the scene tree. This is typically called during scene transitions or when resetting the game state.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="load_all_saved_nodes" qualifiers="static">
			<return type="void" />
			<description>
				Static method that loads and spawns all saved nodes from the current save data. This should be called after loading a save file to restore the saved game state.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_spawn_under_node" qualifiers="static">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="node" type="Node" />
			<description>
				Sets the parent node under which saved nodes will be spawned when loading. If not set, nodes will be spawned under the current scene root.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>
